<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diary</title>
    <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2006 Bill Farmer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 19:09:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Features</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/introduction/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/introduction/features/</guid>
      <description> Entries saved in plain text files Browse entries English, Catalan, Spanish, Italian, Japanese, German, French, Polish, Brazilian Portuguese, Dutch and simplified Chinese Choice of date picker calendars Diary entries may use markdown formatting Optional index page Optional entry template Display media stored in diary folders Display OpenStreetMap maps Print diary entries Share diary entries Add media from media providers Receive media from other apps Receive geo uris from other apps Incremental search of diary entries Add events to calendar Add events from calendar Show today&amp;rsquo;s entry in app widget Dark or light theme for editing Back up entries to a zip file Optional edit cursor position control </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolbar</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/toolbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/toolbar/</guid>
      <description>The toolbar items:
Previous – show the previous entry or today Next – show the next entry or today if next Today – show today&amp;rsquo;s entry And on the menu:
Go to date – show a date picker calendar to select a new date Index – go to index page if set Search – incremental search of diary entry Find all – find all diary entries containing search text Print – print current diary entry Share – share current diary entry Use template – use template for current entry if empty Add time – add the current time to diary entry Add events – add calendar events to diary entry Add media – show a media picker to select media Edit styles – show an editor to edit the custom styles Edit script – show an editor to edit custom javascript Backup – backup entries to a zip file Settings – show the settings </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swipe</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/swipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/swipe/</guid>
      <description>Left and right Swipe left and right in the diary page will show the next or previous day, or in the custom calendar will show the next or previous month.
Up and down Swipe up and down with two fingers in the diary page will show the previous or next month, or in the custom calendar will show the previous or next year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double Tap</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/double-tap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/double-tap/</guid>
      <description>In the formatted view a double tap on the screen will switch to the edit view in approximately the same position in the markdown text. The accuracy is dependent on the text formatting and media in the entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editing</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/editing/</guid>
      <description>In markdown mode the Edit button floating above the page allows editing entries. The Accept button restores the formatted view. A long touch on the button hides it until the device is rotated or a long touch on the page.
See Markdown for markdown syntax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrolling</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/scrolling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/scrolling/</guid>
      <description>Scrolling the page up will temporarily hide the floating button. Scrolling down restores it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/search/</guid>
      <description>You may search diary entries, the search will update as text is entered into the search field. Use the search widget or keyboard action button to find the next match. To find and edit text, search in the markdown view, and then double tap where you want to edit. This will switch to the edit view at about the right place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find All</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/find-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/find-all/</guid>
      <description>You may find all diary entries that contain the current search text. This menu item will only appear while the search widget is active. A dialog will pop up with a list of matching entries. Touch an entry to open that entry. You may repeat this or refine the search text to find the desired entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Index Page</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/index-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/index-page/</guid>
      <description>You may use an index page. If an index page is set the app will start on that page unless receiving media from another app.See Links for the syntax for links to other diary entries and external sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Template</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 19:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/template/</guid>
      <description>You may use an entry template. If a template is set it will be copied to today&amp;rsquo;s entry if it is empty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Widget</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 19:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/widget/</guid>
      <description>The widget will show as much of the entry as will fit in the size chosen. Images, maps, and other media will not display because of android widget limitations. Bullet points do not work very well, but can be constructed using HTML entities so they appear the same in the widget:
&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;bullet;&amp;amp;nbsp; Test item&amp;lt;br&amp;gt; • Test item</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/help/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/using/help/</guid>
      <description>There is a help, a test, an example styles file and an example script file, which may be copied in to an entry for reference if required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/text/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/text/</guid>
      <description>You may receive text clips from another app. A date picker will pop up. The text will be appended to the entry selected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/media/</guid>
      <description>You may store media in the diary storage folders and reference them in diary entries, so markdown text ![cat](cat.jpg) will display cat.jpg stored in the current month folder which is Diary/&amp;lt;year&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;month&amp;gt; on the sdcard. You may either add media from media providers like file managers or image managers or receive media sent by other apps. Media added will be added at the current cursor position. Media sent by other apps will pop up a date picker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latex</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/latex/</guid>
      <description>Diary doesn&amp;rsquo;t support LaTeX, but it is possible to use an external site to add LaTeX formatted images.
![Math](http://www.sciweavers.org/tex2img.php?eq=\sum_{i=1}^{n}x_{i}^{2} &amp;amp;bc=cornsilk&amp;amp;fc=black&amp;amp;im=jpg&amp;amp;fs=24&amp;amp;ff=arev) \sum_{i=1}^{n}x_{i}^{2} If you don&amp;rsquo;t intend to change the image, you can copy it and use that instead, which will then work offline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Svgbob</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/svgbob/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 15:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/svgbob/</guid>
      <description>Diary doesn&amp;rsquo;t support text diagrams, but will display SVG images produced by an online editor Svgbob Editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/links/</guid>
      <description>You may put links in diary pages, so [DuckDuckGo](https://duckduckgo.com) will show a link to DuckDuckGo. Links will be followed if touched. Use the back button in the toolbar or the navigation bar to return to the diary page. Links to other diary pages may either be a relative reference to the entry file [Sunday](25.txt), or use a date URI [Whenever](date:17/10/2017). Use your local convention for short form numeric dates (UK: dd/mm/yyyy, US: mm/dd/yyyy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maps</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/maps/</guid>
      <description>You may put OpenStreetMap maps in diary pages with a geo URI ![osm](geo:&amp;lt;lat&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;lng&amp;gt;). Geo uris received from other apps will be converted to ![osm](geo:&amp;lt;lat&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;lng&amp;gt;) syntax in the diary entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Events</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 09:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/events/</guid>
      <description>You may add an event to the calendar by adding a line to a diary entry which begins with an at symbol (@) followed by a time and an event title @ 10:30 Dentist. An event will be added to the calendar when the entry is saved. A colon will be added after the &amp;lsquo;at&amp;rsquo; symbol when the event has been added @:10:30 Dentist. Use the Calendar app to remove or edit events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cursor Position</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/cursor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 09:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/cursor/</guid>
      <description>You may put a line in an entry to control or remember the edit cursor position. This will not appear in the markdown view. Put [&amp;lt;]: # on a line for the start of an entry, [&amp;gt;]: # for the end of an entry. Put [#]: # for the cursor position to be remembered. There should be no other text on the line. The current cursor position will be added when the entry is saved [#]: # (nnn).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styles</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/styles/</guid>
      <description>You may add custom styles to the markdown formatting by placing a styles.css file in the Diary/css folder, which will replace the built in styles file which simply limits the width of images to the page width. Use the built in editor to create a styles file. You must use the editor accept tick button to save the edits.
Caution – There is no such thing as a markdown syntax error, but syntax errors in a styles file may cause unpredictable results and affect all diary pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripts</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/content/scripts/</guid>
      <description>You may add custom javascript to be loaded into all diary pages by placing a script.js file in the Diary/js folder. Use the built in editor to create a script file. You must use the editor accept tick button to save the edits. Errors in the script will be logged by the WebView which displays the page. See Javascript tutorial.
If you want to use javascript libraries or write a large script it might be a good idea to use the Google Closure Compiler to check and minimise your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/manage/backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/manage/backup/</guid>
      <description>You may create a backup of all your entries in a zip file. The file will have the same name as the diary folder, default Diary.zip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sync</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/manage/sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 09:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/manage/sync/</guid>
      <description>Android cloud storage apps when last tested appeared not to be capable of syncing a real storage folder on the device. However Syncthing does just that and can sync your diary folder with other devices and desktop computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SD Cards</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/manage/sd-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/manage/sd-cards/</guid>
      <description>Android allows removable SD cards to be used like a USB stick or as part of the device storage. Storing diary entries on a removable SD card not part of the device storage may work on some devices, but is not supported. Adding media may also work, but may not be persistent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings</title>
      <link>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/settings/settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billthefarmer.github.io/diary/settings/settings/</guid>
      <description>Use custom calendar – Use custom calendar that shows diary entries rather than date picker calendar Use markdown – Use markdown formatting for diary entries Folder – Change diary entry storage folder. Caution – diary entries and styles will not be moved Index – Set an index page. Use the date picker to choose a date. Template – Set a template page. Use the date picker to choose a date.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
